<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Daniel Lombraña González</title><link href="http://daniellombrana.es/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://daniellombrana.es/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://daniellombrana.es/</id><updated>2012-09-16T00:00:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>Feynman's Flowers</title><link href="http://daniellombrana.es/feynmanflowers.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-09-16T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Daniel Lombraña González</name></author><id>tag:daniellombrana.es,2012-09-16:feynmanflowers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Feynman's Flowers is a &lt;strong&gt;citizen cyberscience project&lt;/strong&gt; developed for &lt;a href="http://dev.pybossa.com"&gt;PyBossa&lt;/a&gt; where the researchers invite the volunteers to &lt;strong&gt;measure the orientation of a molecule&lt;/strong&gt; (that look like a flower) on a crystalline metal surface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project is studying &lt;a href="http://www.ucl.ac.uk/~ucanchi/PyBossa/Molecules/molecules.html"&gt;magnetic molecules&lt;/a&gt; to understad how they can be used to make the smallest possible “spintronic” devices, in which charge (electronic) and spin (magnetic) properties can be used together. In the future, this would allow us to make devices that can do more and also use less energy.
This is the first project of its kind in this area of physics, applying hte power of crowd-sourcing to help understand images created by a scanning tunnelling microscope (STM).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feynman’s Flowers is named after the famous scientist &lt;em&gt;Richard Feynman&lt;/em&gt;, who in his 1959 talk entitled &lt;em&gt;“There’s plenty of room at the bottom”&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="volunteer thinking"></category><category term="PyBossa"></category></entry><entry><title>ForestWatchers.net</title><link href="http://daniellombrana.es/forestwatchers.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Daniel Lombraña González</name></author><id>tag:daniellombrana.es,2012-01-01:forestwatchers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;ForestWatchers.net is a citizen cyberscience project where volunteers from all over the world can help in assessing deforestation from satellite images.
The project currently have two running web applications:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best Tile&lt;/strong&gt;. Volunteers help selecting the less cloudy image for the same are from satellite images.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deforested Areas&lt;/strong&gt;. Volunteers help to identify deforested areas (even in indigenous or federal conservational areas) by drawing polygons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://forestwatchers.net" class="btn btn-large btn-primary"&gt;&lt;i class="icon-globe"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Check the project!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="volunteer"></category><category term="thinking"></category><category term="PyBossa"></category></entry><entry><title>PyBossa</title><link href="http://daniellombrana.es/pybossa.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-11-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Daniel Lombraña González</name></author><id>tag:daniellombrana.es,2011-11-01:pybossa.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;PyBossa is an open-source framework that allows professional and amateur scientists to run web applications (that can be deployed in &lt;a href="http://crowdcrafting.org"&gt;Crowdcrafting.org&lt;/a&gt;) for solving problems where the human minds are required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The source code is hosted in &lt;a href="http://github.com/PyBossa"&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; and it is possible to fork it and run your own instance without problems. The project provides three application templates:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Image pattern recognition&lt;/strong&gt;: in this case, &lt;a href="http://crowdcrafting.org/app/flickrperson"&gt;Flickr Person Finder&lt;/a&gt; that shows how you can classify pictures obtained from Flickr.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geo-coging&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href="http://crowdcrafting.org/app/urbanpark"&gt;Urban Parks&lt;/a&gt; an application that shows you a web map that a volunteer has to browse in order to find an urban park.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PDF file transcription&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href="http://crowdcrafting.org/app/pdftranscribe"&gt;PDF transcribe&lt;/a&gt; a simple application that allows you to transcribe directly PDF files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The PyBossa framework is used by the international project &lt;a href="http://forestwatchers.net"&gt;ForestWatchers.net&lt;/a&gt; in order to allow volunteers to assess deforestation in the forests of the world.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="volunteer thinking"></category><category term="PyBossa"></category></entry></feed>