<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Daniel Lombraña González</title><link href="http://daniellombrana.es/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://daniellombrana.es/feeds/project.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://daniellombrana.es/</id><updated>2012-09-16T00:00:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>Feynman's Flowers</title><link href="http://daniellombrana.es/feynmanflowers.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-09-16T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Daniel Lombraña González</name></author><id>tag:daniellombrana.es,2012-09-16:feynmanflowers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Feynman's Flowers is a &lt;strong&gt;citizen cyberscience project&lt;/strong&gt; developed for &lt;a href="http://dev.pybossa.com"&gt;PyBossa&lt;/a&gt; where the researchers invite the volunteers to &lt;strong&gt;measure the orientation of a molecule&lt;/strong&gt; (that look like a flower) on a crystalline metal surface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project is studying &lt;a href="http://www.ucl.ac.uk/~ucanchi/PyBossa/Molecules/molecules.html"&gt;magnetic molecules&lt;/a&gt; to understad how they can be used to make the smallest possible “spintronic” devices, in which charge (electronic) and spin (magnetic) properties can be used together. In the future, this would allow us to make devices that can do more and also use less energy.
This is the first project of its kind in this area of physics, applying hte power of crowd-sourcing to help understand images created by a scanning tunnelling microscope (STM).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feynman’s Flowers is named after the famous scientist &lt;em&gt;Richard Feynman&lt;/em&gt;, who in his 1959 talk entitled &lt;em&gt;“There’s plenty of room at the bottom”&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="volunteer thinking"></category><category term="PyBossa"></category></entry><entry><title>ForestWatchers.net</title><link href="http://daniellombrana.es/forestwatchers.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Daniel Lombraña González</name></author><id>tag:daniellombrana.es,2012-01-01:forestwatchers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;ForestWatchers.net is a citizen cyberscience project where volunteers from all over the world can help in assessing deforestation from satellite images.
The project uses the open source &lt;a href="http://daniellombrana.es/pybossa.html"&gt;PyBossa&lt;/a&gt; framework and has currently two running web applications:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best Tile&lt;/strong&gt;. Volunteers help selecting the less cloudy image for the same are from satellite images.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deforested Areas&lt;/strong&gt;. Volunteers help to identify deforested areas (even in indigenous or federal protected areas) by drawing polygons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Best Tile&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This application was developed to help the researchers to clean satellite images from clouds. Basically, the application shows pictures of the same area but taken on different days, so the users can actually select the best tile, or in other words, the tile with less clouds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" class="btn" href="http://forestwatchers.net/pybossa/app/besttile"&gt;&lt;i class="icon-cog"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Check the application&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a target="_blank" class="btn" href="https://github.com/ForestWatchers/timeline"&gt;&lt;i class="icon-github"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Source Code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Deforested Areas&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This application builds on top of the previous one, using the cleaned images, to allow the users to mark deforested areas by drawing polygons on top of the deforested areas. This application shows also information in different layers regarding:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Indigenous areas&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Federal protected areas&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hydrography&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" class="btn" href="http://forestwatchers.net/pybossa/app/deforestedareas"&gt;&lt;i class="icon-cog"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Check the application&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a target="_blank" class="btn" href="https://github.com/ForestWatchers/deforestation"&gt;&lt;i class="icon-github"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Source Code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Video&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/syyJ_bEbAtI?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://forestwatchers.net" class="btn btn-large btn-primary"&gt;&lt;i class="icon-globe"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Check the project!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="volunteer"></category><category term="thinking"></category><category term="PyBossa"></category></entry><entry><title>PyBossa</title><link href="http://daniellombrana.es/pybossa.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-11-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Daniel Lombraña González</name></author><id>tag:daniellombrana.es,2011-11-01:pybossa.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;PyBossa is an open-source framework that allows professional and amateur scientists to run web applications (that can be deployed in &lt;a href="http://crowdcrafting.org"&gt;Crowdcrafting.org&lt;/a&gt;) for solving problems where the human minds are required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The source code is hosted in &lt;a href="http://github.com/PyBossa"&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; and it is possible to fork it and run your own instance without problems. The project provides three application templates:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Image pattern recognition&lt;/strong&gt;: in this case, &lt;a href="http://crowdcrafting.org/app/flickrperson"&gt;Flickr Person Finder&lt;/a&gt; that shows how you can classify pictures obtained from Flickr.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geo-coging&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href="http://crowdcrafting.org/app/urbanpark"&gt;Urban Parks&lt;/a&gt; an application that shows you a web map that a volunteer has to browse in order to find an urban park.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PDF file transcription&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href="http://crowdcrafting.org/app/pdftranscribe"&gt;PDF transcribe&lt;/a&gt; a simple application that allows you to transcribe directly PDF files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The PyBossa framework is used by the international project &lt;a href="http://forestwatchers.net"&gt;ForestWatchers.net&lt;/a&gt; in order to allow volunteers to assess deforestation in the forests of the world.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="volunteer thinking"></category><category term="PyBossa"></category></entry><entry><title>LHC@Home: Test4Theory</title><link href="http://daniellombrana.es/test4theory.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-10-01T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Daniel Lombraña González</name></author><id>tag:daniellombrana.es,2010-10-01:test4theory.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://cern.ch/lhc"&gt;LHC@home&lt;/a&gt; is a platform for volunteers to help physicists develop and exploit particle accelerators like &lt;a href="http://cern.ch/public/en/lhc/lhc-en.html"&gt;CERN’s Large Hadron Collider&lt;/a&gt;, and to compare theory with experiment in the search for new fundamental particles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By contributing spare processing capacity on their home and laptop computers, volunteers may run simulations of beam dynamics and particle collisions in the LHC’s giant detectors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The platform has two active projects:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sixtrack&lt;/strong&gt;: studies the LHC machine and its upgrade to understand the fundamental laws of the universe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Test4Theory&lt;/strong&gt;: researches about the elusive Higgs particle with a virtual atom smasher.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Test4Theory project is innovative because it has been the first BOINC project using the virtualization technology to run CERN simulations in commodity computers. The project uses the open source VirtualBox hypervisor to run an instance of the &lt;a href="http://cernvm.cern.ch/"&gt;CernVM virtual appliance&lt;/a&gt; that connects to the CERN servers to download the required libraries and dependencies in order to run the simulations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project has been featured in popular &lt;a href="http://lhcathome2.cern.ch/media"&gt;news sites&lt;/a&gt; like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-14488797"&gt;BBC&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.discovery.com/space/hunting-the-higgs-boson-from-home-110811.html"&gt;Discovery Channel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.zdnet.co.uk/news/emerging-tech/2011/08/09/cern-taps-home-pcs-for-virtual-atom-smashing-40093652/"&gt;ZDNet&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://arstechnica.com/science/news/2011/08/virtual-particles-cern-updates-lhchome.ars"&gt;Ars Technica&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://lhcathome2.cern.ch/media"&gt;etc&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Web tools for the project&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project has been extended with several web tools that will help the volunteers to get more feedback from the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Top users and Billionaires club&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project provides an alternative &lt;em&gt;credit&lt;/em&gt; system for the volunteers based on the simulations carried out within the volunteer's computers. This metric has been used to create a list with the &lt;a href="http://www.citizencyberscience.net/t4t-webapp/stats/"&gt;top 20 users&lt;/a&gt; of the project, listing who is contributing more of their time to the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on this ranking system, a &lt;a href="http://www.citizencyberscience.net/t4t-webapp/stats/club.html"&gt;Billionaires Club&lt;/a&gt; was created as a time line adding the users that have simulated more than 1 Billion events thanks to their contributions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" class="btn" href="https://github.com/citizen-cyberscience-centre/t4t-stats"&gt;&lt;i class="icon-github"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Source Code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Mozilla Firefox Add-on&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to help the volunteers to monitor their contributions, a &lt;a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/firefox/addon/test4theory-stats-checker"&gt;Firefox Addon&lt;/a&gt; has been created. This add-on allows the users to get their latest contributions to the project via the MCPLOTs API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" class="btn" href="https://github.com/citizen-cyberscience-centre/t4t-firefox-addon"&gt;&lt;i class="icon-github"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Source Code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Mozilla Firefox Marketplace Application&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This app stills in the review mode but can be fully tested in the &lt;a href="http://nightly.mozilla.org/"&gt;Android Firefox Nightly version&lt;/a&gt;. The web application allows the users to monitor from their Android tablet or smartphone their contributions to the project. This application uses also the MCPLOTs API and it works also in the desktop version (even in Chrome).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" class="btn" href="http://daniellombrana.es/t4t-app/"&gt;&lt;i class="icon-cog"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Demo application&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a target="_blank" class="btn" href="http://github.com/teleyinex/t4t-app/"&gt;&lt;i class="icon-github"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Source Code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Test4Theory simulations Web Graphical User Interface&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project runs all the simulations within the Virtual Machine, so showing the progress to the users using the standard BOINC screensaver, it is not possible unless a server is run in the Virtual Machine. For this purpose, a web server was installed in the Virtual Machine and a simple web application is served and shows the progress and simulations carried out by Virtual Machine in any modern web browser. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" class="btn" href="http://www.citizencyberscience.net/t4t-webapp/"&gt;&lt;i class="icon-cog"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Demo application&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a target="_blank" class="btn" href="https://github.com/citizen-cyberscience-centre/t4t-webapp"&gt;&lt;i class="icon-github"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Source Code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=_"blank" href="http://cern.ch/lhc" class="btn btn-large btn-primary"&gt;&lt;i class="icon-globe"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Check the project!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="volunteer computing"></category><category term="BOINC"></category></entry></feed>